Charles Fries

Software Developer

4329 Surita Street Sacramento, CA 95864

T: +1 (916) 801-9352

charliefries@icloud.com http://charlesfri.es

Profile

Incredibly passionate, committed, and consistent software engineer, with a great attitude and productive mindset. More than three years of experience working on my own projects or with teams, designing, publishing, and maintaining applications for OS X, iOS, Windows, the web, using technologies like Swift, C++, and more. Proficient in developing full application systems using APIs, databases, backend processing, and file management.

Experience

Founder, Figure Inc.; Sacramento, CA - 2013-Present

- Founded company during my senior year of high school, along with two of my friends, that designs and develops applications for iOS, OS X, and the web.
- Developers of EyeMusic, an app that allows people who have difficulty seeing navigate through their music and audiobooks on iPhone and iPad.

Cashier, Emigh Hardware Company; Sacramento, CA - 2013-2014

- Held a part-time job during high school at my local family-owned hardware store. Maintained the merit of being the store's youngest employee.
- Responsibilities including cashiering and assisting customers find the correct parts and tools for their projects.

Software Engineer, Jesuit Robotics; Sacramento, CA - 2012-2014

- Was a Member, Software Developer, and later Head Software Developer of Topside Software for Jesuit Robotics, a robotics team associated with my school.
- Team competed in and won annual college competitions (MATE ROV) against the likes of MIT, Purdue University, Arizona state, and other international colleges from Russia, Egypt, Hong Kong, and Iran.
- In my final year, wrote the entire remotely operated vehicle's (ROV's) topside control software in cross-platform C++ (using the Qt framework).

Education

Cuesta College; San Luis Obispo, CA – 2015-Present University of Washington; Seattle, WA – 2014-2015 Jesuit High School; Sacramento, CA – 2010-2014

Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C++, PHP, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Applications: Git, Xcode, Qt Framework, Parse BaaS, Heroku, MySQL, FTP, Microsoft Office

Systems: OS X, iOS, Windows, Linux (Ubuntu, Debian) Hardware: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Basic Servers

References

http://github.com/charlesfries http://linkedin.com/in/charlesfries

Please Contact for Person or Additional References